I put a poll up on YouTube where people
like to
vote for the ice cream that I want me to
make they everyone chose uh stabilizer
video for xanthan gum
I also had Biscoff gelato on there
I really wanted to eat it so I made that
one too
let's go
[Music]
so unless you've been living under a
hedge for the last 10 years
probably even longer than that Biscoff
is a caramelized kind of cinnamon
flavor
for lack of a better description
they were originally little little
biscuits that
you get on your hotel
pillow and then next to your coffee when
you were down having your breakfast in a
hotel and then they exploded much like
Nutella did in the world and now Biscoff
is everywhere it's reasonably high in
sugar it's very tasty I like it so let's
make some gelato with it
so for the Biscoff gelato we're going to
start with our milk in the pan and we're
gonna add in our stabilizers mixed with
a little bit of sugar and then we're
going to combine the rest of our sugar
with our milk powder and Pop That Into
The Mix as well it if you have problems
with milk powder dissolving properly
like I do over here then this is the
best way around it it dissolves almost
instantly without any problems
once you've got it in you can then add
in your Biscoff Spread and make sure
that's completely dissolved in your mix
as well
once it comes up to a little bit higher
temperature and your Biscoff Spread has
completely dissolved add in the small
amount of cream required for this gelato
mix that in nicely bring it up to
temperature for your stabilizers mine is
60 to 65 degrees so 59.4 close enough
and then we're going to take it off the
heat and pop it in a container where
we're going to completely chill it down
for three to four hours once it's
completely chilled you're going to take
it out the fridge give it one final stir
and then pop it in your machine to churn
every machine is different mine took I
think 15 minutes 15 16 minutes for this
batch and then load up your tubs as you
would do normally pop it back in the
freezer for at least four hours
[Music]
it's been out of the freezer for five
six minutes it's gelato so it needs to
be served at a slightly higher
temperature than ice cream
again gelato is high sugar low fat if
you want to see the ice cream version
that I made of this so American style
ice cream then I'll put a link in the
description below and I put a little
picture of it somewhere here which shows
exactly what it looked like and the tub
that my wife did for it she doesn't like
the tub but I was quite happy with it
anyway let's get some scooped up see
what it's like
oh
fine
let's I can smell it I can smell the the
kind of cinnamon
I'm assuming it's cinnamon
I should have had a look really
let's see what it tastes like
[Music]
it's nice the best coffee flavor comes
through nicely it's a nice texture I'd
say the stabilizer amount is
really close to being too much so I'll
adjust the recipe below slightly
um
I've done a whole video on stabilizers
I'm going to do lots of smaller videos
and stabilizers gelato uses more
stabilizer because there's much less fat
in there so
you need that stabilizer to create a a
product or an ice cream that will last
in your freezer without it you'll put it
in the freezer it will go solid as a
rock you'll have to defrost it for ages
to eat it scoop it whatever then by the
time you put it back in the freezer
you've started this this Thor and freeze
cycle that ends up just destroying your
ice cream
but this has got a really nice flavor
it's it's cinnamon coming through but
that caramelized I don't know what it is
a caramelized sugar it's it's a really
nice unique flavor it is very unique to
to this whole flavor thing there's two
different brand names for it and one in
the UK one in America and I think
there's another brand name for it
somewhere else in Europe just you know
what it is
or put pictures of all the different
various names that it's got over the
world across the world on the screen but
again a nice simple one to make low fat
nice and cheap not a lot of cream so if
you want a gelato that's got Biscoff
written all over it then give this one a
try thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe and I'll
see you next time
[Music]
foreign